Guide to the Freewater Production Films and Records, 1967-2003 and undated UA.09.13.0005
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Freewater Productions Films
1967-2003 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Freewater Productions
UA.09.13.0005
55 Linear Feet
Freewater Films is a student-run programming committee within the Duke University Union (DUU) responsible for both screening and producing films. Film exhibitions have included weekly and summer series, as well as special event screenings featuring particular directors, actors, or genres. As a film production resource, Freewater has provided grants of film stock, equipment, processing, lab work, and technical instruction to members of the Duke community. The collection includes paper records and various film and tape elements produced by Duke students in the making of their original films. Formats include 35mm film, 16mm film, 8mm film, Betacam SP cassettes, audio cassettes, VHS cassettes, DAT tapes, as well as DVDs. The collection also includes some paper documentation associated with particular films, as well as publicity materials and subject files. Film topics include North Carolina environmental issues, poverty in Durham, political rallies, faculty interviews, campus construction, and student performances. Also included are fictional films on psychological, philosophical, or romantic themes, which feature familiar campus locations such as Perkins Library, the Duke Gardens, the Chapel, or the Duke Hospital. The collection also includes compilation tapes of entries from the annual Hal Kammerer Film Competition, as well as film experiments undertaken during Freewater film workshops. The collection is organized chronologically, then alphabetically by film title. In cases where the creators had grouped multiple reels of a particular film into a small box or a can, these groupings were denoted as reel 1-3 of 3, etc. Where available, synposes written on film cans were summarized and included in this finding aid. The majority of these synposes were written by Freewater Productions participant Benjamin Epps.
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 24-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
Collection is open for research. However, original audiovisual materials are closed to patron use. Use copies are available in the collection.
Provenance
The Freewater Productions Films were received by the University Archives as a transfer in Office of Student Activities and Facilities in June 2007.
Historical Note
Freewater Films is a student-run programming committee within the Duke University Union (DUU) responsible for screening and producing films. It is overseen by the DUU Programming Council.
The committee's origins can be traced to 1969, when the Mary Duke Biddle Foundation gave funds for students from the Duke University Union Visual Arts Committee to make a 16mm film. In November 1970, several students produced an original film entitled Dying, using a 16mm Bolex camera borrowed from the DUU. The following year, Dying went on to win first prize at the Association of College Unions' 1971 International Film Festival.
Freewater soon established its mission in two categories: film exhibition and film production. By Spring of 1972, the film exhibition program was comprised of two weekly film series. One of these took place on Thursday evenings, and featured independent, educational, or niche films. The other series took place on Friday evenings, and featured more recent and popular films. The Friday series provided much of the revenue needed for both the Thursday series, and the film production activities of Freewater members. In addition to these two series, Freewater also sponsored a ten-week summer film series as well as several film festivals devoted to particular genres, actors, or directors. Additionally, it arranged visits by film directors and actors on campus, as well as community outreach initiatives, such as a children's film series, and discounted tickets for underprivileged youth.
As a film production resource, Freewater provided grants of film stock, equipment, processing, lab work, and technical instruction to members of the Duke community. It also funded several independent studies and one Duke course on filmmaking. During the 1970s-1990s, Freewater's Production Coordinator organized a weekly film workshop geared toward beginning and intermediate filmmakers at Duke, focusing on techniques such as animation and graphics. Initially, the organization only had the equipment to produce and process 16mm black and white film, and did most of the processing tasks in-house, in the basement of the Old Chemistry Building on Duke's West Campus. Prints of student-made films were often shown during film series held at Duke and at national screenings; additionally, monitors in the Flowers Lounge often showed some of the films.
Freewater also provided use of their equipment for projects by the Duke Hospital (for producing a commercial) and the Anthropology Department (for producing a documentary on primate research). In some Duke courses, students were allowed to produce films for academic credit; for example the 1982 course Politics and the Media allowed students to incorporate original film-making projects. Other Freewater projects included documentaries on Duke professors, North Carolina environmental issues, and political rallies in Washington, D.C. Many of the films present fictional narratives featuring scenes from Duke campus, including Perkins Library, the Duke Gardens, the Chapel, and the Duke Hospital.
In the Spring of 1974, Freewater absorbed the videotape committee of the Union to coordinate expertise between tape and film experts; they continued to champion experiments with videotape as a new medium. Currently, it is divided into two separate committees: Freewater Productions and Freewater Presentations.
Duke University. Dept. of Cultural Anthropology; Duke University. Chapel; Duke University -- Students; Durham (N.C.); Documentaries (motion picture genre); Student activities -- North Carolina; Duke University. Sarah P. Duke Gardens; Amateur films; Student unions -- North Carolina; Duke University. University Archives; Duke University -- Freewater Productions Films; Duke University
- Freewater Productions Films: 1971, 9 items
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains films produced in 1971.
  - Anti-War Demonstration
    Synopsis from container: documentary footage of Mayday protest in Washington DC. Includes footage of protesters, tear gas, helicopters, police, U.S. Army, National Mall, and U.S. Capitol building.
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 950 ft. (Box 1)
    - Betacam SP, 7 min. (Box 36)
      Tape also includes: Round Two, Dying, Passage, Duke University Union Promo, The Tale of Quasi-Hobo, WXDU Trailer.
  - Dying (1971)
    Directed by Andy Berlin and Chan Smith. From container: A woman's surrealistic encounter on an island.
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, sd., b&w, reel 1 of 2, 350 ft. (Box 1)
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, sd., b&w, reel 2 of 2, 280 ft. (Box 1)
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 2, 325 ft. (Box 1)
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, si., b&w, reel 2 of 2, 325 ft. (Box 1)
    - Regular 8mm Positive, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 125 ft. (Box 1)
    - Optical Sound, 16mm, sd., reel 1 of 1, 325 ft. (Box 1)
    - Betacam SP, 9 min. (Box 35)
      Tape also includes: Round Two, The Tale of Quasi-Hobo, Passage, Duke University Union Promo, The One I Love, Anti-War Demonstration.
  - Howard (1971)
    Directed by Jude Cassidy and Ross Spears.
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, sd., co., reel 1 of 1, 600 ft. (Box 1)
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 400 ft. (Box 1)
- Freewater Productions Films: 1972, 2 items
  Contains films produced in 1972.
  - Passage (1972)
    Directed by Doug Scott.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, sd., b&w, reel 1 of 1, 170 ft. (Box 1)
    - Betacam SP, 4 min. (Box 35)
- Freewater Productions Films: 1973, 1 item
  Contains films made in 1973.
  - Any Old Kind of Day (1973)
    Directed by Mick Ramsey and D. Johnston
    - Positive Print, 16mm, sd., b&w, reel 1 of 1, 1200 ft. (Box 1)
- Freewater Productions Films: 1974, 2 items
  Contains films produced in 1974.
  - Portsmouth (1974)
    Directed by Bill Schmindheiser.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 750 ft. (Box 1)
  - Swing Low (1974)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 400 ft. (Box 1)
- Freewater Productions Films: 1976, 3 items
  Contains films produced in 1976.
  - A Little Night Music (1976)
    - 1/2-inch Open Reel Audiotape, reel 1 of 1, 175 ft. (Box 2)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 100 ft. (Box 2)
  - The Last Tentacle in Paris (1976)
    Directed by Milbre Burch.
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 350 ft. (Box 2)
- Freewater Productions Films: 1977, 18 items
  Contains films produced in 1977.
  - Graphic Arts Reception with Vernon Pratt and Brother Joseph (1977)
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, 10 ft. (Box 2)
    - Reversal Original, Regular 8mm, reel 1 of 1, 250 ft. (Box 2)
  - Pure Prarie League Concert (1977)
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, 250 ft. (Box 2)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 150 ft. (Box 2)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 275 ft. (Box 2)
  - Student-Faculty Basketball Game (1977)
    - Reversal Original, Regular 8mm, reel 1 of 1, 150 ft. (Box 2)
  - University Center Project (1977)
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, si., co., reel 1 of 4, 60 ft. (Box 2)
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, si., co., reel 2 of 4, 75 ft. (Box 2)
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, si., co., reel 3 of 4, 10 ft. (Box 2)
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, si., co., reel 4 of 4, 75 ft. (Box 2)
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, reel 1 of 2, 125 ft. (Box 2)
      Clay mural project.
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, reel 2 of 2, 35 ft. (Box 2)
    - Reversal Original, Regular 8mm, reel 1 of 1, 175 ft. (Box 2)
      Groundbreaking.
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 10 ft. (Box 2)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 100 ft. (Box 2)
      T-shirts, Dope Shop.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 1 of 2, 50 ft. (Box 2)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 2 of 2, 50 ft. (Box 2)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 225 ft. (Box 2)
- Freewater Productions Films: 1978, 5 items
  Contains films produced in 1978.
  - Footage (1978)
    Directed by Pam Hoge. From container: Somebody's pair of feet wake up and go jogging, cross-cut with pictoral similes.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 120 ft. (Box 2)
  - Interviews (1978)
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, si., co., reel 1 of 2, 250 ft. (Box 2)
      From container: Outtakes.
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, si., co., reel 2 of 2, 250 ft. (Box 2)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 175 ft. (Box 2)
  - Windsong (1978)
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1, 120 ft. (Box 2)
- Freewater Productions Films: 1979, 3 items
  Contains films produced in 1979.
  - Pipeline Polly (1979)
    From container: Rough cut of girl hiding in garbage bin and getting dumped.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 150 ft. (Box 2)
      From container: Optical Answer Print.
  - The Last Giggle (1979)
    From container: A girl steals money from her policeman-boyfriend, who stole it.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 140 ft. (Box 2)
      From container: Silent Answer Print.
  - The Lost Last Reel of the Birth of a Nation (1979)
    Directed by David Young. Soundtrack by Lee Erwin. The film is a spoof on the D. W. Griffith film The Birth of a Nation.
    According to explanatory notes, this reel contains an alternate ending to The Birth of a Nation. From container: The Freewater Film Society was given the task of restoring this film, transferring it from its original volatile, somewhat decayed nitrite stock to modern safety film. This was painstakingly done under the direction of David Young with the assistance of Valerie Gertner, Laura Hambleton, Avery Rimer, Jose Berger, and David Walder. An appropriate soundtrack, Lee Erwin playing music for D. W. Griffith classics on the Fox-Capitol Theatre Wurlitzer, has been added for the modern audience.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, sd., b&w, reel 1 of 1, 420 ft. (Box 2)
      Explanatory page moved to Documentation series.
- Freewater Productions Films: c. 1970s, 16 items
  Contains films made during the 1970s that did not contain a specific date.
  - Celebration of Spring (c. 1970s)
    This film is also included on University Center Compilation reel, also in Box 2.
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, si., co., reel 1 of 3, 80 ft. (Box 2)
      In can with 2 reels of magnetic sound.
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, si., co., reel 2 of 3, 20 ft. (Box 2)
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, si., co., reel 3 of 3, 220 ft. (Box 2)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 2, 80 ft. (Box 2)
      In can with 2 reels of reversal original.
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 2 of 2, 20 ft. (Box 2)
  - Circus (c. 1970s)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 75 ft. (Box 2)
  - Saturday Night in Heat (c. 1970s)
    Directed by Quinton Q. Qualles, Jr.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, sd., co., reel 1 of 1, 300 ft. (Box 2)
      From container: Optical Sound Answer Print.
  - Schaefer Acceptance (c. 1970s)
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, 50 ft. (Box 2)
    - Reversal Original, Regular 8mm, 175 ft. (Box 2)
  - Spud B-ball (c. 1970s)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 2, 20 ft. (Box 2)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 2 of 2, 40 ft. (Box 2)
  - The One I Love (c. 1970s)
    From container: Workshop film.
    - Betacam SP, 2 min. (Box 35)
      Tape also includes: Round Two, The Tale of Quasi-Hobo, Passage, Duke University Union Promo, Dying, Anti-War Demonstration.
  - The Perfect Game (c. 1970s)
    Directed by Ned Earle.
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, reel 1 of 2, 1200 ft. (Box 2)
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, reel 2 of 2, 1200 ft. (Box 2)
  - [University Center Compilation Reel] (c. 1970s)
    Includes: Circus, Schaefer Acceptance, Celebration of Spring.
    - Reversal Original, Regular 8mm, reel 1 of 1, 175 ft. (Box 2)
  - [University Center Compilation Reel] (c. 1970s)
    Includes footage of University Center, Dean Griffith, forest, workshops, Union retreat, and 1975 speech by Terry Sanford.
    - Reversal Original, Regular 8mm, reel 1 of 2, 100 ft. (Box 2)
    - Reversal Original, Regular 8mm, reel 2 of 2, 100 ft. (Box 2)
- Freewater Productions Films: 1980, 6 items
  Contains films made during 1980.
  - 8 & 1/4 (1980)
    Directed by Jeff Davis. From container: Pole vaulting film.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, 180 ft. (Box 3)
  - Electron Correlation & the Chemical Bond (1980)
    Directed by D.N. Barton and W. Luken.
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, sd., co., reel 1 of 1, 300 ft. (Box 3)
  - Once Upon a Bus (1980)
    Directed by Mark Eshman. From container: A guy gets on a city bus and starts dreaming about the party he was at and girl that he met there.
    - Reversal Original, Super 8mm, co., reel 1 of 1, 220 ft. (Box 3)
  - Squirrel Hide (1980)
    Directed by Paul Reni.
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 360 ft. (Box 3)
    - DVD Master Copy (Box 3, Video-disc D04581748.)
  - The Primal Horde (1980)
    Directed by Jeff Bennett. From container: A guy kills himself, only to become dissatisfied with heaven.
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, sd., b&w, reel 1 of 1, 250 ft. (Box 3)
  - Untitled (1980)
    - Reversal Original, Regular 8mm, reel 1 of 1, 600 ft. (Box 3)
- Freewater Productions Films: 1981, 5 items
  Contains films made in 1981.
  - Documentary of Anti-Abortion March in Washington, D.C. (1981)
    Directed by Randy Knight, Carolyn Finney and Nathan Schneiderman.
    - Reversal Original, Super 8mm, sd., co., reel 1 of 1, 500 ft. (Box 3)
  - Ultimate (1981)
    Directed by Northrop Davis.
    - Positive Print, 35mm, reels 1-4 of 4, 350 ft. (Box 3)
      From container: B-roll.
  - Visible Man (1981)
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, sd., b&w, reel 1 of 1, 300 ft. (Box 3)
  - Untitled (1981)
    Directed by William Nichols. From container: Plot: Something about toast and a young couple's relationship at home.
    - Reversal Original, Super 8mm, co., reel 1 of 2, 500 ft. (Box 3)
    - Reversal Original, Super 8mm, co., reel 2 of 2, 100 ft. (Box 3)
- Freewater Productions Films: 1983, 3 items
  Contains films made in 1983.
  - Round Two (1983)
    Directed by Ben Allenoff, featuring Todd Holland and Calista Woodbridge.
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, sd., b&w, reel 1 of 1, 340 ft. (Box 3)
    - Betacam SP, 9 min. (Box 35)
      Tape also includes: Dying, Passage, The Tale of Quasi-Hobo, Dying, The One I Love, Anti-War Demonstration, WXDU.
- Freewater Productions Films: 1984, 1 item
  Contains films made in 1984.
  - A Medical Scutwolf in Durham (1984)
    Directed by Lars Erickson. From container: Doctor becomes werewolf. Includes footage of Bryan Center and Duke Hospital.
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1, 180 ft. (Box 3)
  - Untitled (1984)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 300 ft. (Box 4)
- Freewater Productions Films: 1985, 10 items
  Contains films made in 1985.
  - Dusk (1985)
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, 240 ft. (Box 4)
      From container: Processed ECO Original.
      Edge Number Register moved to Documentation series.
  - Muffin Man (1985)
    Directed by Andy Falcon and Osceola Refetoff. Film includes computer graphics and animation, with a science-fiction theme.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, co., reel 1 of 1, 1220 ft. (Box 4)
      From container: Work Print Outtakes.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, co., reel 1 of 1, 1200 ft. (Box 4)
      From container: EKTA-Sound Print/ Answer Print No. 1.
    - Betacam SP, 29 min. (Box 35)
  - The Fuse (1985)
    Directed by Matthew A. Borten.
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 2, 800 ft. (Box 4)
      From container: Soundtracks.
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 2 of 2, 700 ft. (Box 4)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 600 ft. (Box 4)
      From container: Answer Print.
  - The Tale of Quasi-Hobo (1985)
    Directed by Marshall Becker and John Neumark. From container: the tale of a 'down to earth' guy who doesn't quite approve of modern world. Blues soundtrack.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 300 ft. (Box 4)
      From container: A & B Rev. Snd. Answer Print.
    - Betacam SP, 9 min. (Box 35)
      Tape also includes: Round Two, Dying, Passage, Duke University Union Promo, The One I Love, Anti-War Demonstration, WXDU.
  - Untitled (1985)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 300 ft. (Box 4)
  - Untitled (1985)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 400 ft. (Box 5)
      Directed by Doug Mankoff. From container: ECO Original.
  - Untitled (1985)
    From container: Interview, man and woman, cheesy romance cuts.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, co., reel 1 of 1, 450 ft. (Box 4)
- Freewater Productions Films: 1986, 8 items
  Contains films made in 1986.
  - Dreamwalker (1986)
    Directed by David J. Wright.
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 4, 180 ft. (Box 5)
      From container: Processed ECN Original.
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 2 of 4, 60 ft. (Box 5)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 3 of 4, 140 ft. (Box 5)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 4 of 4, 220 ft. (Box 5)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, co., reel 1 of 3, 180 ft. (Box 5)
      From container: One-lite color-positive work print.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, co., reel 2 of 3, 120 ft. (Box 5)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, co., reel 3 of 3, 180 ft. (Box 5)
  - Oblivion: A Science Fiction Adventure (1986)
    Directed by Dave Pratt, Fred Stein, and Jim LeClair.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, sd., co., reel 1 of 1, 1200 ft. (Box 39)
      Item moved to Oversized series.
- Freewater Productions Films: 1987, 2 items
  Contains films made in 1987.
  - Unintended Exposures (1987)
    Directed by Michael Bayer.
    - Betacam SP, 60 min. (Box 35)
  - Untitled (1987)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 70 ft. (Box 5)
      From container: UNF.
- Freewater Productions Films: 1988, 53 items
  Contains films made in 1988.
  - Academics Now (1988)
    Directed by Michael G. Mitchell. Includes shot of professor smoking.
    Edge Number Registers moved to Documentation series.
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 4, 140 ft. (Box 6)
      From container: Original ECN.
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 2 of 4, 950 ft. (Box 6)
      From container: Original ECN, A & B rolls, B-wind S/T.
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 3 of 4, 1000 ft. (Box 6)
      From container: Original ECN, A-Roll.
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 4 of 4, 1000 ft. (Box 6)
      From container: Original ECN, B-Roll.
    - Negative, 16mm, reels 1-8 of 13, 500 ft. (Box 6)
      From container: ECN.
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 9 of 13, 225 ft. (Box 6)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 10 of 13, 175 ft. (Box 6)
    - Negative, 16mm, reels 11-13 of 13, 360 ft. (Box 6)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 150 ft. (Box 6)
      From container: Processed ECN.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 80 ft. (Box 6)
      From container: Work Print Credits, Outtakes.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 1100 ft. (Box 6)
      From container: Check Print.
  - Library Dream of Death (1988)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, co., reel 1 of 1, 150 ft. (Box 7)
      From container: Color Work Print Edit.
  - Pig (1988)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 400 ft. (Box 7)
  - The Interview (1988)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 700 ft. (Box 7)
  - The Significant Other (1988)
    Directed by M. Longosz.
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 350 ft. (Box 7)
      From container: 4x Reversal and Scene: Perkins.
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reels 1-4 of 8, 425 ft. (Box 7)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reels 5-8 of 8, 700 ft. (Box 7)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 420 ft. (Box 7)
      From container: A-Wind.
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 2, 460 ft. (Box 7)
      From container: B-Wind.
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 2 of 2, 420 ft. (Box 7)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 2, 400 ft. (Box 7)
      From container: Track B-narration.
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 2 of 2, 400 ft. (Box 7)
      Mixing Cue Sheet moved to Documentation series.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 480 ft. (Box 7)
      From container: Workcut Print.
  - Woods off the Hi-Way (1988)
    Directed by Duncan McLean and Johnathan Brenner.
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, sd., co., reel 1 of 2, 280 ft. (Box 8)
      From container: Processed 4x Reverse Original.
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, sd., co., reel 2 of 2, 180 ft. (Box 8)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 3, 300 ft. (Box 8)
      From container: ECN Original.
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 2 of 3, 40 ft. (Box 8)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 3 of 3, 140 ft. (Box 8)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 3, 160 ft. (Box 8)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 2 of 3, 600 ft. (Box 8)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 3 of 3, 360 ft. (Box 8)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 2, 150 ft. (Box 8)
      From container: ECN original; heads; trims; roll 1.
      Edge Number Registers moved to Documents Series.
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 2 of 2, 450 ft. (Box 8)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 2, 280 ft. (Box 8)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 2 of 2, 250 ft. (Box 8)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 900 ft. (Box 8)
- Freewater Productions Films: 1989, 35 items
  Contains films made in 1989.
  - All Hallow's Eve (1989)
    From container: Obvious comparison between sacred and secular; Basic soundtrack contrasting religious chants and hymns with frat party babble; and Monster hiding in the toilet.
    - Negative, 16mm, co., reel 1 of 1, 200 ft. (Box 9)